<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<curriculum>
  <pdf>Saskatchewan Ministry Of Education</pdf>
  <outcomes>
    <goal_section>
      <goal_heading>Treaty Relationships (TR)</goal_heading>
      <outcome id="TR">
        <identifier>TR</identifier>
        <outcome_text>TR6: Analyze the concepts, structures and processes which have been developed for the purpose of treaty implementation.</outcome_text>
        <indicators>
          <indicator>
            <p>Research the various structures and processes that have been created in an effort to honour treaties.
</p>
            <p>Describe how the full implementation of the treaties is expected to bring positive economic implications for all people of Saskatchewan.
</p>
            <p>Explore the concept of sovereignty as related to First Nation peoples.
</p>
            <p>Explore the concept of sovereignty as related to Métis peoples.</p>
          </indicator>
        </indicators>
      </outcome>
    </goal_section>
    <goal_section>
      <goal_heading>Spirit and Intent of Treaties (SI)</goal_heading>
      <outcome id="SI">
        <identifier>SI</identifier>
        <outcome_text>SI6: Analyze the importance of the preservation and promotion of First Nations and Métis languages.
</outcome_text>
        <indicators>
          <indicator>
            <p>Express how one’s cultural identity is influenced by language.
</p>
            <p>Explore initiatives in Canada that contribute to the preservation and restoration of First Nations languages.
</p>
            <p>Describe how the loss of language impacts cultural identity (e.g., importance of ceremony, song, dance, storytelling).</p>
          </indicator>
        </indicators>
      </outcome>
    </goal_section>
    <goal_section>
      <goal_heading>Historical Context (HC)</goal_heading>
      <outcome id="HC">
        <identifier>HC</identifier>
        <outcome_text>HC6:  Analyze how the movement towards the fulfillment of treaty obligations has positively affected all people in Saskatchewan.
</outcome_text>
        <indicators>
          <indicator>
            <p>Examine the impact of urban reserves on livelihood (e.g., economic, social, cultural, environmental).</p>
            <p>Examine how the Federation of Saskatchewan Indian Nations (FSIN) and other organizations supports the fulfillment of Treaties.
</p>
            <p> Investigate how parties to treaty are utilizing the land for economic development opportunities.</p>
          </indicator>
        </indicators>
      </outcome>
    </goal_section>
    <goal_section>
      <goal_heading>Treaty Promises and Provisions (TPP)</goal_heading>
      <outcome id="TPP">
        <identifier>TPP</identifier>
        <outcome_text>TPP6: Investigate the role of the Treaty Table and the role of the Office of the Treaty
Commissioner (OTC) in promoting good relations between signatories.</outcome_text>
        <indicators>
          <indicator>
            <p>Describe the role that Treaty Commissioners play in facilitating the fulfillment of treaty.
</p>
            <p>Investigate and report on the goals and achievements of the Treaty Table and the OTC.
</p>
          </indicator>
        </indicators>
      </outcome>
    </goal_section>
  </outcomes>
</curriculum>